<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-06T16:15:36+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</id><title type="html">aaaronoid</title><subtitle>This is a space for me. You are welcome to drop in and have a look. Here I will ramble and grumble--but mostly--mumble. I will try and be coherent but I can’t promise you.</subtitle><author><name>Adam Aaron</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/courses/Sum-of-many-parts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2018-09-16T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/courses/Sum-of-many-parts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/courses/Sum-of-many-parts/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-sum-of-many-parts&quot;&gt;The sum of many parts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a realistic representation of analogue watercolour takes many small ingredients that work together in unison. We also want to build a method of working that keeps out of our way as much as possible. I have separated my workflow into five main stages, the idea being that we will work through the stages linearly 1-5 resulting in a finished piece of artwork by the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be useful to think of the whole process in terms of the metaphor of a theatre production. Below is a brief overview of each of the five stages. The following sections will then go into each stage in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opening-credits&quot;&gt;Opening credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time we start a new piece we will first copy in a pre-existing file stored outside Procreate with several things already set up for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;act-1&quot;&gt;Act 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-1&quot;&gt;Stage 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;base-file&quot;&gt;Base file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think of this as the performance stage set for our play—the backdrop.&lt;/strong&gt; We will start each piece with a new copy of our Base file. A stack of layers specially set up above our main artwork will influence the colours below and add texture mimicking the structure of the paper. This alone will get us about 80% of the way to a convincing watercolour. I will break this section down into two parts. The first will be practical advice on how to use the file properly. The second will be much more about my decision making process to how I set up the file. The second section will be an entirely optional read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-ii&quot;&gt;Stage II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mark-making&quot;&gt;Mark-making&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the main event.&lt;/strong&gt; Think of this as the actors playing out their lines and movements. We will cover brushing technique and there will also be some helpful tips on how to set up Procreate’s brush sets and colour palettes to best benefit from this workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;act-2&quot;&gt;Act 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part Act 2 is all grunt work. Luckily, we can get the iPad to do most of the repetitive work for us and a lot of the process is the same for every artwork we will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-iii&quot;&gt;Stage III&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;displacement&quot;&gt;Displacement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The intermission. Here we take a quick break from the main show and visit Affinity Photo&lt;/strong&gt; ‘Displacement’ sounds a lot more complex than it is. As watercolour dries it settles into the nooks and crannies of the paper and takes on the shape of the paper texture. This effect is best used with restraint. The end result should only be a subtle effect that adds just that extra bit of realism, it should never retract from the overall piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a distortion filter in Affinity Photo we will ever so slightly warp our artwork to the structure of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-iv&quot;&gt;Stage IV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;edge-darkening&quot;&gt;Edge-Darkening&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The penultimate scene.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most distinctive characteristics of watercolour is the darkened edges it exhibits after it has dried as the pigment has pooled together. I use two approaches to simulate this which work well independently of each other or in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-v&quot;&gt;Stage V&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;post-production-as-necessary&quot;&gt;Post production (as necessary)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conclusion.&lt;/strong&gt; In our final scene we return to Procreate where we will bring everything together and make any small adjustments as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;end-credits&quot;&gt;End credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here will be links to a selection of resources that I have found useful or have influenced me in my approach.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Aaron</name></author><category term="Procreate" /><category term="watercolour" /><category term="workflow" /><summary type="html">Outline of how this course will be broken down.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The idea of a digital sketch collection</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/opinion/digital-sketch-collection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The idea of a digital sketch collection" /><published>2017-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/opinion/digital-sketch-collection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/opinion/digital-sketch-collection/">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;page__lead&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The likes of Instagram, Facebook and Twitter et al leave me cold and numb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Instagram, Good Bye and Good Riddance!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison to an analogue sketchbook there really is no real digital equivalent to me. We live in an age of mass consumption. But are we really &lt;em&gt;consuming&lt;/em&gt; anything? To me the systematic pull-to-refresh and aimlessly scrolling a feed feels more like chewing and then spitting out—a reflex, a mindless habit. To actually consume you also need to digest. The likes of Instagram, Facebook and Twitter et al leave me cold and numb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is simply too much stimulation to take any of it in properly. I started using Instagram as a way to file away my sketches as I produced them. Looking back on them now, there is no story there, no progression. I also don’t remember the last time I went through someone’s whole Instagram like I would sitting with their sketchbook. Instead I go through a mishmash of loads of peoples work that I may like but it is out of context and does not get the full attention that it deserves. I feel like a zombie and with time I have begun to hate the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still want a place to share my sketches and any thoughts that go along with them. A blog format seems a better way to do that. Whether other people appreciate my take on the world remains to be seen, but I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to output my thoughts somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Aaron</name></author><summary type="html">Dear Instagram, Good Bye and Good Riddance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/site/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world" /><published>2017-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/site/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/site/hello-world/">&lt;p&gt;I’m not 100% sure what this little corner of the internet will be for just yet. I started this site out of frustration for feeling like I want to share something but I am not sure what. We will see…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Aaron</name></author><summary type="html">The best laid plans of mice and men…</summary></entry></feed>